Tiffany Wang

Graduate Full-stack software developer

NZ Citizen

021 022 58062

Email: thiffanyjun@hotmail.com

Portfolio: <u>tifff-wang.github.io</u>
Github: <u>github.com/tifff-wang</u>

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/tifff-wang

About me

Kia ora, I'm Tiff! I'm a graduate full-stack software developer with an education background. I bring a wealth of skills from my teaching experience, particularly my ability to empathize, communicate, plan, and work in a team.

I'm proficient in full-stack technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, React, JavaScript, TypeScript, C#, .NET, PostgreSQL, NodeJS, ExpressJS, as well as REST APIs, unit testing, and GitHub. Additionally, I have experience in AWS Cloud computing services, including EC2, Cognito, RDS, and Amplify. I possess a strong dedication to continuous learning and improvement. One of my biggest strengths is having a keen eye for identifying pain points and crafting effective solutions.

Experience

Nov 2023 - Recent

Software Developer Intern

JC&T Tech

- Developing the back-end for an expense tracker application using C# and .NET framework.
- Utilising AWS Cognito SDKs to establish authentication APIs and implementing AWS RDS with PostgreSQL to build cloud databases.

Jun 2023 - Oct 2023

Full-stack Software Developer

Dev Academy Aotearoa · Apprenticeship

- This was a 15-week, 800-hour full immersion software development bootcamp that mimics the real-world Agile development team with multiple projects that focus on both web development and people skills.
- Tech stack includes HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Knex, SQLite3, Node.js, Express.js, RESTful APIs, Unit Testing, and GitHub.
- In my final project, <u>Tiff's Donuts</u>, I acted as the Product Owner with five other team members where we developed a web application using threeJS and React. I had the opportunity to take the lead in introducing and implementing React Three Fiber, a technology not covered in our bootcamp. This experience was truly valuable as it showcased our team's dedication to collaborative problem-solving and our ability to adapt and learn on the fly.

Aug 2022- Jun 2023

Freelance Web Designer

Freelance

- Provided logo design and UI/UX design for several volunteer-driven side projects including web interface design and Webflow building. Feel free to check my design wonderland: https://www.tiffwang.co.nz/.
- Demonstrated proficiency in Adobe Creative Suites, prototyping and design thinking skills.

Nov 2021- Jun 2023

Centre Administrator

Tots on Triton Childcare

- Demonstrated excellent customer service and communication skills.
- Streamlined administrative workflow, resulting in a 30% reduction in task time and significant productivity and cost savings.
- Contributed in promoting the centre by utilised my design skills to create flyers and banner that were displayed in Asian supermarkets.
- Served as the go-to tech support for teachers encountering issues with their computers and printers.

Nov 2019- Nov 2021

Career Break and Parental Leave

Multiple Ventures

• I had my pregnancy and parental leave while exploring the possibilities of career change including studying and completing a Graduate Diploma of Professional Accounting and Foundation Level Certified Tester from ASTQB.

Apr 2017- Nov 2019

Head Teacher

New Shoots Childcare Centre

- Took on a leadership role in guiding the team to deliver high-quality education and care for children.
- Facilitated collaborative discussions to develop tailored strategies that successfully transformed the classroom into the most calm and organised one.
- Designed an intuitive program planning board that effectively improved the consistency of centre program planning.

Feb 2013- Apr 2017

Registered Teacher

Evolve Education Group

- Engaged in close collaboration with a team of educators to ensure the best outcomes for children.
- Consistently recognised by colleagues and parents for my ability to identify children's needs, demonstrating strong observational and empathy skills.

Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Amazon Web Services | Nov 2023

Certified Tester Foundation Level ASTQB | Sep 2022

Education

Web Development Training Scheme | Level 6

Dev Academy Aotearoa | 2023

Diploma in Digital Design (Web and Graphic Design)

Yoobee College of Creative Innovation | 2022 - 2023

Graduate Diploma in Professional Accounting (Average A)

Auckland University of Technology | 2021-2022

Bachelor of Teaching

New Zealand Tertiary College | 2012 - 2014